mylist.com 2013-11-27

# myList: Privacy Policy

Though lists are shared with friends (that’s the fun of myList), your personal information belongs to you, and you determine when/if it will be shared.

myList™ Privacy Policy

Effective January 2012

myList provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of the myList Application. This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through use of the Application. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy within the Application. You are advised to consult this policy regularly for any changes. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our myList Terms of Service.

As used in this policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

Information Collection and Use

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Application, services, features and content, to provide you with the most relevant information for your needs and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Application.

Personally Identifiable Information (PII).

When you successfully install the myList Application, you consent to share certain PII provided to us from Facebook including information that can be used to identify or contact you. PII includes, but is not limited to, your name, your location, and other basic information you have shared with Facebook. By using this Application, you are allowing myList to access your Facebook information and you are agreeing to the Facebook Terms of Use regarding your use of the Application via Facebook.

  1. We use your PII primarily to provide the Service and administer your inquiries.

  2. We also collect the other information that you provide as part of the administration and personalization of your experience on myList (e.g., without limitation, age, friend list information, and individual preferences) (“Non-Identifying Information”).

  3. We use your PII (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) primarily to provide the Service, personalize your user experience, and administer your inquiries.

  4. Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your PII if it were combined with other identifiers in a way that enables you to be identified. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information (for example, your viewing preferences). We may combine your PII with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other myList Users (defined below) to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how our Application is used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver information to you according to your preferences.

  5. We may also use your PII to contact you with myList messages, marketing or promotional information from myList and/or the suppliers of the things in your list and other communications that may be of interest to you. myList may also post on your behalf. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications. You may, at any time, change the information and rights granted to myList by using the Facebook-provided myList app settings page. Some of the information provided is required to use myList and while you may elect not to provide this information, this choice will disable the App. 

  6. Log Data. When you visit the Application, our servers record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website (“Log Data”). This Log Data may include information such as the browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Application, pages of our Application that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for within our Application, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Application and the Service and for the Application’s technical administration, to increase our Application’s functionality and to better tailor our Application to our visitors’ needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Application again, it will recognize you and serve information appropriate to your interests. We do not treat Log Data as PII nor use it in association with other PII, though we may aggregate, analyze and evaluate such information for the same purposes as stated above regarding other Non-Identifying Information.

Facebook Cookies

Like many websites, our Application use “cookies”; to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer or mobile device’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Application. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Application, to better understand how you interact with the Application and to monitor aggregate usage by myList Users and web traffic routing on the Application. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site, Application and Service and then close your browser. Third party advertisers on the Application may also place or read cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Application or all functionality of the Service.

Phishing

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are highly objectionable to myList. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, login information, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website.

Information Sharing and Disclosure

When you use the myList Application, other myList Users will see your name, your lists, including the name you give your lists, things you added, and information that you share. If you choose to provide PII within the thing itself or in the list names, other myList Users will see this additional PII. We strongly recommend that you guard your sensitive information and not provide any information in myList that you would not want shared with others. 

Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information. 

We may share aggregated information that does not include PII and we may otherwise disclose Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your PII.

Service Providers. 

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Application-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Application’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Application and Services are used. These third parties have access to your PII only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Facebook API 

We allow the Application on behalf of users to post information and invitations to Facebook. When information is posted by the Application, your Facebook settings will determine where and how the information is shared. You may, at any time, change the information and rights granted to myList by using the Facebook-provided myList app settings page. Some of the information provided is required to use myList and while you may elect not to provide this information, this choice will disable the App. 

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement. 

myList cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including, but not limited to, subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of myList or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

Business Transfers. 

myList may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your PII, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.  In this event, the owner of these assets will be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service.  

Deleting Your Information

You may delete the myList application completely using the Remove App function in the Facebook App Settings page. We may retain an archived copy of your information as required by law, or to provide additional services for you and/or for other legitimate business purposes.

Security

We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored PII (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site or via the Application in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

International Transfer

Your PII may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to use myList, myList transfers PII to the United States and processes it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Links to Other Sites

Our Application contains links to other websites. If you choose to leave the myList Application by “clicking on” a thing shown on myList, banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

Our Policy Toward Children

You are required to log in to Facebook in order to use myList. As an application within Facebook, myList is not available to children under the age of 13\.  We do not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of 13.  If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with PII without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy@mylist.com.  

Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@mylist.com](mailto:privacy@mylist.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy).
